Hello, everyone.
I am Sun Ying, a teacher at the Dragon Art Academy of Tianjin University of Technology.
Today, I want to share with you the new path of the deaf students who have no sound and no trace of clothing.
You may have heard of Tianjin University of Technology, but you may not know that there is a Dragon Art Academy of Technology in Tianjin University of Technology.
Our school specializes in recruiting deaf students.
Today, I am going to share with you the situation of our school, the student's learning analysis, including how we solve the problem of hearing loss,
how to learn the profession of washing clothes, and how CLO can help them with their employment.
I want to give you a brief introduction.
Our school is run by the government of Tianjin and the Chinese government.
It was founded jointly by the Chinese People's Union of Disabled People.
It is also the first school in China to recruit deaf students.
Our predecessor is the Special Education Department of Tianjin University of Technology.
It was established in 1991 and recruited the first deaf students.
In 1997, we officially established the Dragon Art Academy of Technology in Tianjin University of Technology.
This is an introduction of our school.
We have about 30 years of learning experience.
Our current major includes clothing and clothing design, product design, visual communication, computer, and network engineering, etc.
In 2001, we and the National Dragon Art Academy of Technology of the United States,
the Russian Bauman National Technical University, and the Japanese Judo Technical University of Technology
have jointly launched a network education project related to creating deaf people.
Our students also pay great attention to external communication.
We also participated in the opening ceremony of the Beijing Chamber of Commerce.
In 2013, we opened a new mode, which is the mode of comprehensive education,
which allows hearing students to enter the class and major of the class of the student.
In 2013, we also expanded our major to 10 major design majors.
In 2018, we also realized the academic recognition of Chinese and American hearing students,
including the first deaf student.
In 2019, we officially received the training qualification of hearing and math students.
In 2025, we also established the Dragon Art Academy of Technology.
In 2015, we also established the Dragon Art Academy of Technology.
In 2016, we established a new minor major.
This major is also dedicated to the help and support of CLOU,
which is non-disabled digital development and sustainable design.
This is the overall situation of our school.
Our students are also special.
So I would like to introduce the situation of our students here.
Our students are deaf people, that is, deaf students.
So in terms of learning,
they will encounter some difficulties.
First of all, it is a lack of information.
In the classroom, we teach with sign language.
We teach professional knowledge through sign language.
However, there is a clear difference between sign language and Chinese.
This is like between Chinese and English.
It has a problem of deviation in the language.
At the same time, it also has vision.
It mainly uses vision to identify information.
So it may miss some important points of knowledge when it is learning to lower its head.
Or there is some deviation in understanding of your sign language.
So it causes a decrease in the absorption rate of knowledge.
Especially some abstract concepts,
and professional vocabulary of clothing,
all of them will have some obstacles in their understanding.
The second difficulty is that
our students are deeply aware of the problems in art education.
Our problem is that
these abstract concepts and theories
are challenging for deaf students.
It is a lack of emotion and experience.
So they lack an effective connection channel.
The traditional teaching mode
is actually not suitable for us.
It is not suitable for our students' learning.
The third one is that
it is difficult for them to integrate into society.
Because of the obstacles in hearing,
they sometimes get misunderstood
or get into difficulties.
Especially in the fourth grade,
their internship stage,
the internship stage for finding a job,
is relatively prominent.
It is difficult to find a relevant professional internship position.
But in fact,
our students still have many advantages.
For example,
our students,
because of the lack of hearing,
they are visually sensitive.
They are also very unique in the field of art.
And they have a strong ability to move their hands.
They can make up for the lack of hearing
through touch and vision.
And they are less disturbed.
They are very focused.
They are also patient.
As for the profession of clothing,
it is a non-language expression.
Right?
Art is more inclusive.
So,
it is actually more suitable for deaf people.
based on the characteristics of our students,
we have been exploring and solving the way of breaking through.
Through the learning of visual and touch,
the two channels,
to increase the absorption rate of knowledge in students.
For example,
we use CLO,
LCD,
or VR virtual venue,
and so on,
to create a kind of
visualized teaching,
immersive interaction experience,
to solve the problems of
deep cognitive and physical difficulties.
At the same time,
in their thinking,
we develop the three-layer cognitive layer,
and improve their
theory of thinking.
It also has a certain help.
For example,
through value,
lead to thinking creation
and ability to advance,
to transmit professional knowledge.
I also hope that
through technology,
to assist the cultivation and transformation of traditional culture.
In the fourth aspect,
I will introduce specifically
our negative energy path,
because our students are more special.
So,
our classroom,
I put these two videos
in the classroom,
some of the teaching scenarios.
That is,
we have to explain professional knowledge through sign language.
At the same time,
there are some real language translation systems,
that is,
subtitles will be displayed on this screen.
Mainly,
it depends on sign language.
So,
we need to use a multi-mode teaching method.
Through sign language,
visual,
symbolic,
and tactile,
use materials to convey emotions,
so that students can have a better understanding.
Finally,
through the way of creation,
to experience,
so that they can master the knowledge related to clothing,
and professional understanding of vocabulary.
The second main negative energy path,
we build this kind of
production and learning platform,
that is,
through the way of school cooperation.
In recent years,
we have introduced CLO in our school,
including the intelligent embroidery system,
including the translation software of Xunfei,
and so on.
That is,
using technology
to provide more space
for the teaching of deaf people
and the design of clothing professionals.
So,
we have to use technology
to provide more space
for the teaching of deaf people
and the design of clothing professionals.
So,
we have to use technology
to provide more space
and possibilities.
So,
our online teaching session
is all about
using sign language,
and then
the comprehensive application
of three-dimensional imitation CLO,
and then
AI
to realize three-dimensional embroidery,
which serves the teaching of clothing professionals.
So,
the specific
connection
of this path,
let me briefly introduce it.
Because
at the end of 2023,
we introduced CLO
in our class.
So,
we introduced CLO
in our class.
We introduced CLO
So,
we immediately
developed a new
talent training program
for students in the 2024
and then
we introduced CLO
into the training system.
But,
our students
in the 2021,
2022,
and 2023
training programs
cannot be done
casually.
But,
we want to
let some students
to use it
earlier
and to benefit earlier.
So,
we took
a more
moderate way,
in the current training program,
we chose
some courses
without changing
the original course
teaching content.
In this way,
each course
compresses
4-8 classes.
Then,
we put
the teaching content
of CLO
separately
in
multiple
courses.
For example,
the second grade.
In the second grade,
our main course
is
the
fashion technique,
professional
industrial knowledge,
and the
fashion structure.
We put
CLO
in these three courses.
Then,
we learn
some basic knowledge
of CLO separately.
For example,
sewing,
shirt,
pants,
and this kind of simple
style change,
the use of 3D pen,
etc.
This is a
second-grade class.
So,
in the third grade,
we will
connect
some special courses.
For example,
currently,
we have
the computer
embroidery class.
We will
put
CLO
and
the
embroidery
CAD
board
together.
Then,
use CLO
to make
a virtual presentation.
Then,
we will
use
this
embroidery
machine
to
make
the
finished
product.
Finally,
we use AI.
It is very convenient
to use AI
to make
a small video
like this
through
this
training.
In the third grade,
we have
some special courses,
such as
art design
to be
realized
with CLO.
This is
what we
students did
before.
Before CLO,
we were
divided into groups
to make
small pieces.
Then,
CLO
is very troublesome.
It is a small piece.
It is very
time-consuming.
But,
with CLO,
we can
make
a single
blueprint
of CLO
through
making
CLO
to
make
it virtual.
This
greatly
improves
our
learning efficiency.
We can
use
the
virtual
presentation
of CLO
and
the
virtual
presentation
of CLO.
We can
use
the
virtual
presentation
of CLO
and
the
virtual
presentation
of CLO
to
make
CLO
into
a
virtual
presentation
of CLO.
We can
make
CLO
into a virtual
presentation of CLO.
It is
extremely
helpful
to our
students because
they may
need some
information
in class.
We should
watch
the videos
repeatedly
to
make
it
easier for
them.
The
most important
thing
in the
fourth
year is
graduation
design.
Because there were many graduate students who were not in the school at that time, so we chose some of the students in the school at that time.
CLOE gave us training, including classroom training, and took the students to listen to CLOE's class together.
Then we used CLOE in the graduation design that the students did at that time.
In 2025, all the students will be able to use CLOE to do the graduation design, including to participate in the competition.
The design of this outdoor costume is also the result of our students' participation in the Tianjin fashion competition.
In addition,
because we joined CLOE in the course,
the evaluation system of the entire work was appropriately adjusted,
strengthening their visual impact and weakening their hearing,
making their thinking more tangible.
Then we also made a change in the evaluation standard weight ratio.
Then there is also the way to train in the competition.
We used CLOE to lead the students to actively participate in a lot of innovation and entrepreneurship competitions,
and also achieved very good results.
Including the second digital recovery design competition,
we also took the students to do the Tang Dynasty Zanhua City Painting,
and the third New Year's Eve painting.
We basically participated in each.
Then the last part is the employment situation.
In fact, our students' employment is very, very difficult.
Why do I say this?
Because first of all,
when the deaf person is looking for a job opportunity,
when they are applying for a resume,
it may be a problem to contact them.
When the company calls them and needs an interview,
they may not be able to contact them,
they may not be able to communicate,
because they can only send a text message.
So their internship, employment,
on the one hand,
is to rely on teachers and schools to recommend work for them.
On the other hand,
it is also to promote the employment of the disabled community.
I would like to express my special gratitude to the Shanghai New Year's Eve Cologne.
This is when we went back to Cologne last year.
Then Mr. Zhang also introduced the overall situation of Cologne to us.
Then we have a student from the 24th century
who has also been an intern at Cologne,
and then stayed at Cologne.
That is,
Cologne provides a very good job opportunity for our hearing students.
And with this great tolerance and kindness,
they have built a platform for them to grow.
So it makes these children more confident on the road to their dreams.
So I summed up the situation of students' employment in recent years.
What they mainly do is,
these work related to clothing,
mainly rely on teachers to recommend.
For example,
they have done this clothing assistant,
like this one clothing company in Guangzhou,
to do this kind of
fashion design of sandalwood,
including the customization of stage makeup.
These are all recommended by our teachers to them.
Then,
it is Cologne's new wash,
specifically made clothing modeling,
including this laser cutting,
cutting,
CAD,
and so on.
Like this year's student,
we recommend them to go to this one in Hebei Province.
The company of that cheongsam,
at that time,
we recommended them to do computer embroidery,
and the CAD board.
Later,
this company found that
this student can also do Cologne.
They thought,
oh, this is great.
Their company doesn't have this technology yet.
So the boss of that company also told me,
do you have any students who can continue to recommend?
So,
in this process,
in fact,
our students still get a very high evaluation of the employment unit.
In addition,
there may be some students who will switch jobs.
This is impossible.
This is inevitable.
Well,
because the company they found,
for example,
there are some,
but also related to clothing,
for example,
this kind of character design design,
or flat surface design,
such as fashion magazines,
these related flat surface designers,
including the transition to this kind of pattern design,
ah,
the direction of visiting professionals,
to transition,
there are also,
ah,
there are also some of the professionals in the field,
who are also very good at mobility design,
ah,
I also hope that through this platform today there will be some related enterprises
who can see and understand the situation of our students, their students who are hearing-impaired students,
and then be able to provide them with more job opportunities.
I would like to thank CLO again for building a good platform for our children.
Thank you everyone.